just dil se Avast nicly those a Vasco
Sunni man Tsukiji Orchestra that's
exactly what we mean very good very good
and all that to start with something
amazing
well welcome to wellness 360 at home
brought to you by ICS a Lombard
something that we all want to learn
something that we all should learn and
that is all by the mean saw lockup under
lockdown this is all about learning and
being informative and gaining something
more towards wellness every single step
in a last episode it was a laughter riot
where we saw such amazing thing by one
person dr. mother Natalia who taught us
how to laugh and we laughed along and
every day we are practicing that such
that we are happy if you're not doing
that you should be starting to do that
right away first laugh top is the way
out so that was the last episode but
yeah
welcome again to the episode number two
of wellness 360 at home brought to you
by ICS yellow bite so who is with us
today
well somebody who is the finest in
everything she does
who is she nutritionists to stars like
Deepika Padukone Sonam Kapoor Ranbir
Kapoor Shahid Kapoor just also a
celebrated addition to date and
transform the bodies and lives of
thousands of people around the world her
best-selling book released in the year
2012 called eat and delete has been
translated into hindi bengali with
wrathy and Marathi in the year 2017 she
launched her second book called eat til
eat junior a book on trend nutrition and
now launched n4 nourish a children's
book aimed at teaching kids about
nutrition just also had having her own
TV show called the Buddha Makeda show
the food food channel an old radio show
on magic FM and has a regular column in
The Times of India this is also an
entrepreneur she has her own online and
her own line of healthy snacks called as
inertia bill we are very delighted to
welcome in our second episode of
wellness 360 at home the one and only
The Rave popular Pooja Mejia thank you
thank you so much Mithun for the warm
welcome and the warm words of
introduction
pooja Makita welcome to the Wellness 360
at home and just to one thing you know
what along with all that I spoke about
you what is the most amazing part is
that you're also a mother of two
adorable girls and a very important role
you're playing right now so it's such a
delightful thing that you must be going
through totally completely to be able of
course as a mother I don't think there's
any I'm definition that we would like us
to be introduced with without so yes I'm
a very very proud mom of two adorable
girls were any little anymore they're
their girls now and all is good okay so
we can't wait to learn so much for the
next 30 minutes cause our viewers are
live with us the show is live and that'd
be so much learning ahead so yes that
the Wellness 360 at home began with the
one and only Pooja Makita now well
welcome everyone
everyone who's here who is watching the
life with us I think it's a great
initiative taken by ICICI Lombard to
bring wellness into all your homes so I
guess the title of wellness 360 is
clearly a very apt title to give because
at times where we are currently I don't
think anything can be more in
watching than the fact that eating
rights has never been more important
than it is currently right so at times
where we are finally it realization has
hit us all that how important our health
is and the fact that the virus or the
the times where we are in the colvett
virus sees no boundaries it sees no
demarcation of gender of nationality of
religion of caste of height of of
celebrity status rich for the only one
thing that is keeping us apart from
those who need medical intervention
versus those who don't is your body's
innate immunity it has been clearly seen
in studies that have been done on over
the 1 and a half million people that
have been affected with kovat that 80
percent of people who do get kovat stay
a symptomatic or do not require medical
intervention now it's that's a large
percentage of people that we are looking
at 80 percent people will not burden the
already burden medical system and those
80 percent people are clearly those
people who are being able to have their
body's defense mechanisms stronger than
the others so today's session is going
to be all about how we can keep you in
that 80% of complete wellness where your
body has the strength and ability to use
food as your internal kitchen toolbox
pharmacy where you are going to use what
is available in your kitchen to be able
to rev up your immune system to have you
mentally and physically attuned to being
locked inside your homes now we have to
realize that this lockdown is something
that works on us
it works on us emotionally physically
mentally and how we are going to be able
to break free from this how is
that see none of us want to be locked in
right none of us want to not be able to
achieve perhaps the work targets a
socialization target so so many other
things that we had actually decided we
are going to finish before the first
quarter of 2020 right
we all had we all had a lot of to-do
lists that we had to finish but we do
not like the fact that we have been
locked in but according to me if we
learn how to eat right in this period of
lock-in at least we will leave that
period with something positive that came
out of being locked inside your house
because you learned how to control and
get health back into your lives okay how
you can become the boss of your lives
and no doctor no or largest node
cardiologist I batala gist or
nutritionist or a coronavirus can affect
you or your is lives are
responsibilities of other doctors let's
learn how to use this period to nurture
our bodies with good food with good
eating habits that starts from Hell it's
not a diet I'm not going to give you
guys a diet I'm not going to say my plan
is the best plan to follow or you should
only follow X diet and avoid X diet what
I'm going to teach you is how to make
your own diet how to be the boss of your
own food to be able to understand your
body not only in the terms of good
health but also in good looks because
how you how you feel is how you look so
if you want to lose weight or be healthy
or have better skin or have better
energy levels or better stamina or
lesser PMS or letter less of
perimenopause symptoms or aches and
pains and arthritis everything begins
from the food we eat everything starts
with one simple action of hand-to-mouth
which is what I'm going to teach you how
to do it with thought and how we can
work about all of this of course to make
sure that our health in times of COBIT
is within our hands so first let me
start by giving you all five very
important nutrients that all of us must
be focusing in kovat types okay I know
it sounds like a ironic
a weird thing to say but if these are
call the Cova times and I think to be
abreast with them and to be able to
equip ourselves with the information is
what we require because fear is what is
going to is a deadly cocktail we don't
want to be fearing the disease we don't
want to fear anything
what we need is education as a tool to
have more education and therefore
disperse the film right so starting with
the first nutrient that I want to
discuss and that is proteins proteins
are inherently your body's innate
soldiers soldiers that keep your fort
and your body strong our proteins are
something that is very done over in
abundance with when you are in the West
but when we follow an Indian vegetarian
diet proteins are something that kind of
gold lacks in most of our eating habits
in a vegetarian diet proteins are only
found in your pulses legumes dal sprouts
soya bean a little bit of milk and milk
products and nuts and not nuts
so therefore focusing on protein is very
very crucial because if I don't have the
raw material to form the innate soldiers
I can't have a heightened sense of
immunity so proteins at your three main
meals breakfast lunch and dinner must be
done with thought whether it is having a
base and Casilla for breakfast or if you
do eat egg whites they could be great
source of breakfast or if you're eating
like for example an idli with sambar
which is also your protein you want to
do a bowl of sprouted poha so you do
sprouts with poha that is also your
protein having meals lunch and dinner
having some amount of dolls at all meals
is a very important thing and I would
insist that you not only do it for
yourself but also for your parents at
home we are aware that they are at a
higher risk category because as we are
growing older our immunity becomes
weaker and if you have other
comorbidities
for example diabetes blood pressure
cardiovascular disease this immediately
reduces your
immune response and therefore keeps you
more vulnerable to the virus
so therefore keeping good quality of
proteins is going to keep your fought
very very strong moving on to the next
nutrient which is vitamin b12 again why
I address them in this order is because
vitamin b12 is only found predominantly
non-vegetarian food so if we are of a
community or more vegetarians and vegans
we aren't getting enough b12 b12 is not
only important for your nerve health for
your energy levels for your stamina but
most essentially it is crucial for your
immune system the T and B cells which
are the fighter cells in our body are
directly proportional to the mythic Obul
which is the b12 which is got from our
diet it is a vitamin that cannot be made
by the body guys so it has to be
provided by the diet and if you are
having a vegetarian diet sadly there are
no nutritional sources by which you can
do that which is the reason why making
sure that you are having enough amount
of protein is what is going to give you
a the nutrition to form the TB cells and
then the b12 which is going to give the
activity to the TB cells to be active T
and B cells not T V T and D cells to be
active to have your immune system
completely guarded and fought it if you
guys are vegetarian and you all have not
had any b12 supplements for the last six
months I recommend a dose of about
thousand milligrams of b12 thousand
micrograms of b12 to be taken by all
adults on a daily basis for the next two
months thousand micrograms of b12 to be
taken on a daily basis by all adults I
am not recommending this for children I
am giving you adult doses if you have
not taken oral b12 I suggest for the
next two months take that amount because
it's very very important
after b12 we are moving on to the next
vitamin which is vitamin d3 now vitamin
d3 was initially only a thought to be
very important for a bone strength and
therefore giving us good strong bones
and no aches and pains and no knee
but the more and more research is
showing us it is clearly telling us that
vitamin D is proportional to innate
immunity and your susceptibility to the
common cold so the the corona virus is a
flu which is similar to the Rho no virus
no no virus is the common cold and flu
that we are taking okay so if so there
was a study done which was published in
the Journal of Medicine which showed
that those who have low vitamin D levels
are more susceptible to common cold and
flu and taking low dose vitamin D
prevented them from falling sick in
terms of the viral attack so therefore
more researchers currently who are doing
a bit by bit match to match of what
because we do not have that much data or
we do not have subjects to be able to
study what is the effect of nutritional
deficiencies on the corona virus so via
extrapolating data from other correlated
viruses to say okay let's step up the
vitamin D level so that we will put more
percentage of the people in that eighty
percent see it's very clear that those
eighty percent people who are not
requiring medical intervention or are
surviving the virus without any symptoms
are people who have good nutritional
status and do not have compelled
complications that will make them less
susceptible target so vitamin D is one
of them however vitamin D is a
fat-soluble vitamin I will not recommend
that you take large doses without doing
blood investigations at the moment doing
blood investigations is not very easy so
I am going to recommend a low dose
vitamin D for all of you who are
listening in as part of the ICICI
Lombard initiative or 360 degree of
wellness at home is to take 2000 IU of
vitamin D on a daily basis for the next
two months mm are you not the high doses
of sixty thousand international units
which is when you have done blood tests
if you have not done blood tests please
stick to the 2000 IU you can give this
to all adults in your house especially
your parents and
parents because they they are innate
immunity is more important for us to
protect and to safeguard so we've done -
why are white we've done proteins we've
done beach well with our vitamin D let's
move on to vitamin C we all are aware
there is a very strong link between
vitamin C and common cold and flu
vitamin C and collagen formation
collagen formation is equivalent to
mucus for me a mucus formation which
forms the mucous lining in your mouth as
well as your nose as well as your throat
and this mucus lining is the first
barrier to stop the virus from entering
from our nazo oral route you are aware
the virus enters through this route so
if you have greater mucus and collagen
from formation the virus gets trapped
here is killed in here and is pushed out
of a body and does not enter our body to
require an immune response so vitamin C
is extremely easily available in our
foods a la Peru lemons these are all
great sources of vitamin C however being
in a lockdown sometimes availability of
these vegetables and fruits is becoming
little difficult to get our hands on
which is why I am recommending taking an
oral supplementation please do note guys
that I am NOT saying we cannot get
nutrition from food I am just we are at
the moment saying we are using
nutritionist therapeutic we are not
using nutrition for sustenance we are
using nutrition for survival of the
fittest which is why I am recommending
vitamin supplementation I am not ruling
out the fact that you need to eat good
food but this vitamins helps enhance our
immunity to a jumped-up extent which is
why our taking oral supplementation of
vitamin C can also do can help us vastly
I would suggest anywhere between 1,000
to even 2,000 milligrams of vitamin C to
be taken on a daily basis this only
helps us rev up our immunity and keep
our food stronger the last vitamin that
comes in this category is vitamin is
zinc now zinc is a cofactor which is
required for about 180 enzymatic
reactions in our body including those
which are required for iniative
unity more and more research is telling
us that it is this zinc that when it
goes intracellular with the help of the
anti malaria drug which is why we are
using the hydroquinone right which is
the anti malaria drug it takes the zinc
and transports it inside the cell it is
the zinc inside the cell that is
stopping the RNA replication of the
corona virus and therefore killing the
virus and by snipping the problem in the
bud so zinc is a very crucial vitamin it
is available in our nuts and seeds and
green vegetables and our grains as well
but I like I said we are talking about
therapeutic doses so I say I suggest
anywhere between 20 to 30 grams
milligrams I'm sorry 20 to 30 milligrams
of vitamin or zinc to be taken by adults
it is available in various of vitamin
doses if you are looking at a
multivitamin which will allow you all of
this then it is multivitamins don't come
with these doses my dear then which is
why you will have to take them
separately so please do take them
separately 20 to 30 milligrams of zinc
it is available in various vitamin
supplements you'll have to check the
therapeutic name with the availability
of the region that you are in right so I
am okay
so so please do take white zinc as well
zinc is crucial to keep your immunity
factor up now having said does Inc we
are moving on to one a very crucial I
said we're going to be talking about
five so we've spoken about protein b12
vitamin D zinc and last and most
important is water most of us are
sitting at home we are not hydrating
ourselves enough maybe because we are
sitting in air-conditioned or we are
more passively sedentary and we are not
realizing the importance and the
distinguishing between thirst and hunger
most of us are very happily binge eating
all the foods that are tasting good on
our tongue and I will come to that as
the next part of the talk but water is a
very crucial nutrient which is required
for heightened immunity for must
responses cramps your skin your bowel
movements your energy levels your moods
so water is very very crucial I would
suggest we every time the clock strikes
12:00 drink one glass of water drink
half a glass of water or use technology
set reminders every sixty to ninety
minutes to consume at least 200 ml of
water that way you will match your
target of anywhere between two and a
half to three liters of water to be
consumed on a daily basis water is very
very crucial guys and most of us do not
give enough importance to this nutrient
this nutrient is considered to have no
calories it's considered to have no
nutrition no taste so therefore it is
ignored please don't do that so that's a
great thing to do so please make sure
that you're drinking ample amount of
water so those were the five nutrients I
want you to focus on after the five
nutrients I am going to come to four
habits which can be life-saving which
can keep us with our heightened guard
which can use this wellness 360 at home
as an effective tool to be able to take
care of ourselves and our loved ones
okay all that I'm telling you is
applicable to everyone you love please
feel free to give this information
around to everyone that you care about
this is in terms of nutrition this get
only and only do you good see please
remember we are all in a lockdown
because we want to flatten the curve of
the virus but if we are sitting in a
lockdown and we curve the flat of our
body and our body curves then we are
completely defeating the purpose so the
most important the most important habit
that I want you to first pay attention
to is eat food with thought okay yes
these are times where there is stress
there is binge eating there is comfort
eating you want to distract yourself
there's boredom eating it's all put here
me so let's do a little bit of fancy
cooking everyone seems to have become
master chefs at home everyone wants to
bake everyone wants to try their hand to
keep themselves busy I am NOT
don't do it I'm not saying that if you
have to bake you have to bake enough for
the whole building you can make small
amounts to try taste to spread the love
but you don't have to spread the sugar
calories because sugar increases
inflammation kovat virus bothers us
because it increases the inflammation in
our body and causes a cytokine storm in
our body so all foods that are going to
increase inflammation in our body is
already making you at higher risk to
have the COBIT cytokine storm so sugar
is something we have to be very cautious
and careful about don't overdo the oil
and the sugar because those are things
that are going to pull you down and of
course those are things that are going
to curve the flat and although you may
be locked in and may protect yourself
from the virus but if you're going to
gain 4 5 7 kilos in the lockdown then
when you step out you may not of course
you will attract the virus as well but
you are attracting other metabolic
disorders like blood pressure diabetes
arthritis cardiovascular disease and
that is not what we want to do in this
lockdown right the lockdown is not our
choice but taking care of our health it
is our choice
leaving the lock down healthier stronger
mentally and physically can only be done
when our food is given a little bit more
importance so the first habit that I
want you to focus on is to eat with
thought right I am NOT saying never eat
something wrong but what I believe in is
following an 8020 rule
80% of the time eat what your body
requires in terms of proteins water a
balanced diet eating home food we have
no choice there right we are not we're
not eating binge eating Chinese or we
are not ordering in so we are anyways
eating at home so in 80% of the time if
you are eating our fruits and vegetables
are healthy food our dolls falses
legumes a balanced diet our indian thali
is the best guys we don't have to look
left and right to west and east
our Indian Hollies are the best if we
control the sugar and the fact and eat
balanced 80 percent of the times then a
little bit of bad mushy
what your loved ones baked for you about
your daughter or wife for you is
fine
today I was consulting with the client
and he told me Pooja everything is fine
but every day my daughter is making so
every day in the night I'm meeting one
big fat bowl of whatever she's big but
if you are going to if you're going to
wash out the good of everything you're
doing during the day by doing what
you're doing wrong then it's really not
going to help the cause right so that's
what we have to we have to say I'm not
saying never eat it but eat it in small
quantities so an 8020 rule is what works
best the second habit that I want you to
focus on is exercise now exercise is not
something I want y'all to leave your
homes run out go running on this running
in your building or running or running
to a gym or you should have all your gym
equipment or treadmills at home we don't
really need large spaces even if our
home is so small even if we have just
enough space to stand while we are
watching TV to stand up instead of
watching TV sitting down stand up just
do a little bit of spot walking up
nearby an hour of Netflix day clea one
hour of spot walking Kirlia physical
activity is done
now when I say exercise or do some form
of physical activity it helps us not on
one count of weight loss or maintenance
of it it helps you there it releases
happy hormones and endorphins which calm
the cortisol of stress and being locked
in and the ambiguity of tomorrow and
economy and crashes and salaries and
paychecks and do's and EMIs yes everyone
has them but if we are going to be able
to release that kind of stress from our
mind we are also helping our immunity
see we have to remember that we're going
to beat this damn virus okay but if we
are going to be stronger here we're
going to come out of it stronger
otherwise if we are not stronger here
the virus is going to take us over
whether it actually physically attacked
us or mentally mentally derailed us so
if you exercise you are going to have
your your wits by your end your energy
your focus everything is going to be
controlled it's going to cause
exhaustion to cause good sleep which is
going to be the
next habit I'm going to talk about but
exercise helps you on many fronts of
weight maintenance of Achor of immunity
of mental balance and equilibrium so
exercise has many many win-win reasons I
am NOT asking you to huff puff and pant
it could be simple squats jumping jacks
every trainer every person is showing us
home videos if you just google home
workout videos you will find so many but
find the motivation to do it and I would
suggest make it a family affair
let's let six to seven every evening be
your time where the family stands
together either you play a little game
of a catch catch or you just one move
around you do some or everyone does for
jogging everyone does a few jumping
jacks it can be a fun activity that
leaves a lot of happy memories and keeps
you strong
moving on to habit number sorry I'm
losing track of numbers but the next
habit is sleep now sleep is extremely
crucial for your immunity there was a
study done where people were divided
into two groups one was sleep-deprived
when I say sleep-deprived I say anywhere
lesser than seven hours of continuous
sleep for an adult and then there were
those who had adequate sleep both of
them were given a vaccine for the common
cold and flu those who were sleep
deprived from lesser antibodies to
prevent the vaccine from being
successful versus those who had adequate
sleep had greater production of
antibodies and therefore greater
protection against the common cold in
through sleep has a direct correlate to
your immunity sleep has a direct
correlate to mental well-being wear and
tear repair because that is the only
time our body can do it the more we
stick to regular timings of sleep the
better we are helping our body this kind
of principle that we are all following
of everyone staying awake late in the
night binge watching TV shows waking up
late
next morning is not the way to go the
movie follow the circadian rhythm of
light and dark and the earlier we get
into bed and the earlier we wake up like
we wake up and we have clinic and office
and school
the stronger you're going to be mentally
as well as physically so please try to
maintain regular sleep and wake up
timings
please clock 7 to 8 hours of continuous
deep sleep what most people are doing is
sleeping very late in the night
sometimes waking up early in the morning
and then taking long afternoon naps to
cover up for the sleep that is not the
same thing as seven continuous hours of
sleep I strongly urge you to even
recommend this to all the children in
the house they are also having disrupted
sleeps cycles for them not only will it
cause disruption and immunity it will
also cause disruption in growth a growth
hormones are released only at stipulated
hours in the body and if they are not
sleeping at those hours they are not
going to grow not going to grow
physically they are not going to grow
mentally so therefore please be very
strict with the children about sleep and
wake up timings because it is crucial to
keep themselves it is crucial to keep
them strong and it is crucial for their
growth so sleep is a very important
factor I just cannot if I had half hour
I would have done an entire session only
on sleep because it is so important to
keep ourselves balanced mentally
physically emotionally if you do not get
enough sleep you will be more cranky
irritable you will think the whole world
is coming to an end versus when you have
slept you will be more positive you will
look at this approach and this lockdown
with a different set of eyes and will
try to make the most of it versus get
sucked in and become upset angry
depressed and let anxiety attack you so
sleep is extremely crucial and the last
that takes me to the last habit that I
want you all to focus on which is being
positive now yes sleep has a direct so
everything that I speak usually has a
connect good eating habits we need to
good exercise
good sleep and we'll good sleep with
good water will lead to a stronger
immunity and lastly when all of this is
done well the approach in the outlook to
this forced period has to be one which
is positive okay
yes there are a lot of negatives but we
only have to be counting our blessings
in terms of having the privilege of
having a home to be comfortable under
the fact that we have availability of
electricity food internet to keep
ourselves communicating to keep
ourselves educated to keep ourselves
within the Wellness periscope of Health
we are fortunate so what I strongly
practice and recommend is keeping a
small gratitude Journal it could be any
small book which you can label all the
days of the week and you put in every
date and every day right two to three
things that you are thankful for whether
it was whether it was a wellness session
you attended by ICICI Lombard or whether
it was a hub that you sent to your to
your loved ones over and over a video
call or the fact that you've got eggs
this morning or your bindi was available
it could be small happy things but
please please learn to look at more at
this situation more positively or your
chori chori are that the I would suggest
please recommend this to your children
as well write down three things today
that you thought you were fortunate
about because the idea is the more we
throw into the universe that this is
we're going to come out of this happy
and positive that's the way we are
actually going to take care of it and
that's the way we are actually going to
keep ball with it so writing a gratitude
journal is a very easy simple thing to
do it's a practice that we can do it
very very easily so let's just let's
just keep the focus on that so that we
are able to bring we are able to come
out of this happier stronger and more
positive with that I think I open the
forum to answering any queries and
questions that you may
have about food and nutrition because I
think this needs to be interactive and I
need to help you on a personal level as
well so mitten I must say that was one
of the most amazing session and thank
you so much for giving us so much
insight about how one should take care
of the body which is very important how
to draw and increase your community and
most importantly how to be happy so
thank you so much again and as you were
talking to a bunch of questions already
coming in so if you're ready with the
questions I am gonna shoot at you okay
the first question coming to you body
often take who says he's 58 year old and
he is a pure vegetarian and he is not
taking any dinner since last year only
taking a cup of hot milk people sleep
please advise him healthy diet at night
you
ah in the night without a fuel so I just
put coolant in the engine but I don't
bother to put petrol in the car but I
continue to drive it your body is and
relentlessly working machine it works
for you 24/7 even when you're sleeping
skipping meals is not a great idea
because skipping meals is skipping
nutrition a chance in a reason to
nurture this body with what it requires
ah your dinner could be a meal that is
smaller than your lunch I'm not saying
it has to be as big as your lunch
because your physical activity in the
night is much lesser so you're more than
welcome to have a lighter dinner but
please do not skip your dinner it is a
chance that you're missing to do to to
nurture yourself and not teach yourself
so you do not do that a cup of warm milk
is perfect
my husband does that to always post
dinner and one-hour pre-bedtime movie
yellow you could add a little bit of
healthy in it because that's a great
antiseptic antiviral antibacterial
antimicrobial the curcumin in healthy is
the best curve that we have in our
kitchen to fight this war so if you want
to pata pata gargle with it in the
mornings you want to have a turmeric
latte as they call it in America as at
bedtime you want to use
dalinar dollars of these which which in
any case our Indian Holi promotes a
please feel free to use this what I do
with turmeric is I take fresh turmeric
fresh healthy fresh Nimue and fresh
pepper kippa not fresh pepper just
pepper balls I chop the hully the ginger
and the entire nimbu with the skin and I
and I put pepper balls in it and keep
this like a pickle to make for 10-15
days once it becomes a little fermented
I use a teaspoon of this and eat this on
a daily basis with both my meals so that
I get a rush of curcumin my kids have to
have it my in-laws have to have it my
husband has to have it they all make
faces but they all have to have it at
all lunch and dinner because that's the
strong way to keep ourselves strong
absolutely that answers a lot many
questions on unless our next question to
you a puja is by Rohit Sharma who is
asking you a question about how roads
sing rather then how can somebody please
the stamina and what died should they
plan so stamina is a direct equivalent
to good nutrition so there is I wish I
had one secret to say sube eat a lot a
khr much dude pillion autohotkey stamina
bar jelly but sadly there are no
shortcuts in life to get anything no
shortcuts to get good skin or to get
stamina it is directly equivalent to how
well you're taking care of your body so
just like saying I want my car to give a
good average can you suggest one tip
push me away eight tip knee hair you
have to take care of the car as a whole
you have to make
sure that the engine has oiled and the
tires the coolant
blah-blah-blah-blah-blah
so same way when you're taking care of
your diet it has to be well balanced you
should be eating protein in all meals
you should not be skipping meals you
should be drinking ample amount of water
you should be getting good sleep there
has to be gradual build-up of stamina
with gradual exercise good breathing so
there are a lot of things Rohith I wish
I had one answer to give you but
becoming aware that your body requires
food for nutrition I want you all to
please all of you highlight on this that
every bite that you're putting into your
mouth is information it is information
whether I want good skin good hair good
energy good stamina greater immunity no
disease no pain or it is information to
give you diabetes inflammation hair loss
pigmentation PCOD every bite is
information so eat with thought eat that
you are nurturing yourselves eat that
you are the boss and no nutritionist or
doctor should ever be ruling your life
and automatically you will gain
everything that you want because a graph
of my body co modo gage Oh Shi Yi move
up co bodega jo aapko je good hair good
skin good energy good stamina and the
rest thank you so much again pooja
there's one common question that's
coming throughout our Q&A and that is
how do somebody who's a vegetarian can
increase the b12 in their body sadly
only by oral supplementation or by
injections beat well like I said is only
found to dominantly in animal khana so I
cannot tell you please go eat chicken
and mutton and egg whites because that's
not what you're going to do milk and
milk products will have a little bit of
b12 because it is animal food but it's
not enough to keep your immunity and
energy up so sadly for vegetarians
taking oral supplementation like I
suggested thousand micrograms on a daily
basis for the next two months is a good
way to fill up the bank then once
everything becomes easier do a blood
test speak to your GP or your
nutritionist and for for my clients or
my vegetarian clients I usually suggest
a cycle of b12 in a year to take so
check that with your doctor your doctor
will teach you how to do it so the
eight-month clinic our dough month gap
varies monthly Nakano month gap so the
doctor will be able to teach you but as
a vegetarian you must be aware type b12
up to orally lena per day god that's
true by the means of capsules or
injections or eight months that's the
way it goes I'm doing one so I know
about it we have one more question with
a very interesting question puja then
how is that Europeans who are all about
non-wage and they are falling more for
Kobe 19 and usual Indians and this
question is coming to us by somebody
called Kaushik Mukherjee ah trying to
stay there Caucasians are most
susceptible to the covert virus as
compared to Asians that's true I don't
know whether that there is a correlate
there scientifically but what I would
there the virus reach their countries
quicker than it reached us but anyone
whose innate immunity is weakened or
when you have other comorbidities of
obesity of blood pressure diabetes you
are more likely to be victimized by
koban I don't think it is seeing any
barriers in terms of nationality or
religion or epidemiology it is only
seeing the strength and the innate body
immunity in terms of immunity as well as
in terms of comorbidities so they have
they have said that people who are
overweight are X times more likely to be
affected by the virus people who have
diabetes are more likely to affected by
the virus according to me I don't think
there's a demarcation in epidemiology
but there is more in terms of your
health status so all that matters is how
healthy you can keep yourself that much
stronger you're going to keep your body
there were some talk about a BCG vaccine
that we have received in our infancy
which could be
acting as a protective mechanism which
is protecting us versus those countries
where BCG was not given as children but
that is just a theory it could be
possible it's helping us but I may take
BCG but if I am NOT taking other
preventive methods to take care of
myself in terms of sleep water immunity
and nutrition I'm still going to be as
susceptible as someone who has not taken
the BCG that's true that's completely
true it's a theory and one should
believe it or not believe it we have one
more question by n Balasubrahmanyam
whether a diabetic person can take honey
I do not like sugar added sugar in any
form whether it is sugar or honey good
day ma'am rush sugar maple sugar coconut
sugar date sugar these are all different
ways to make us boudu sugar is sugar and
it is empty calories it's giving you no
nutrition it is increasing inflammation
increasing disease increasing aging and
weakening your immune system so I do not
believe in added sugar in for anybody so
clearly it's a big no-no what he was
asking he is free through coffee for
about a month now what should he do to
get rid of this cancel the doctor maybe
isn't the true answer oh yes you
definitely should but maybe taking a
little bit of haldi like I said early
morning haldi water goggles at the
moment it is summer otherwise I would
have told you gargle and drink the
healthy because it will work as an
antiseptic as well inside as well but
right now maybe you could gargle and
drink half of the water and gargle and
spit out the first the remaining half
also if the cough hasn't gone for a
month this is called as chronic cough
and usually chronic cough is related to
acidity I would check factors because of
regard it Asian of the gastric acid it
is causing a recurrence pressure on your
throat which is causing a cough
cross out all the reasons why you could
be having acidity which could be large
gaps and therefore eating large meals
too much alcohol too little water poor
sleep those are all reasons for acidity
please do not believe in just popping an
antacid it is a not a very safe drug to
keep taking people take antacids like
it's gems but that a dependency on
antacids is not a good idea
correct your diet I wish I could give
you more tips but with positive time I
don't know how many tips I can give you
but taking care of acidity is very easy
with a good diet break up your meals eat
often control your caffeine there are
tongues that you need to do but I would
control your acidity and I am sure your
cough will go away thank you so much I
think we'll take two more questions puja
one question for all the vegetarians
because they are the ones were asking
too many questions regarding the b12 and
much more want me to answer their
questions because there if they don't
address these issues they are the lot
that is weaker and more susceptible so
I'm definitely very happy to help them
yes just make sure the ones who are
watching us like that you make sure you
make a note of all the tips the puja is
giving us it's really important you
follow them and trust me once you start
following you will see a better result
in coming days okay quickly two more
question wanna take Kucha one again is
about how to control weight while being
at home all time and by being able to
tell well I think I've answered that in
the whole talk so if you're going to
have like I said a tea time
eighty percent of the time you're eating
right 20 percent a little bit of bad
mushy you're keeping at least 40 to 50
active minutes every day you are
sleeping well you're drinking enough
water so you distinguish between hunger
and thirst and if you're a vegetarian
you're taking oral supplementation's
because b12 is important whiten zinc is
important and good proteins are
important I think if you follow all the
five nutrients that I asked you to focus
on and the four habits that I asked you
to do you will get better
you will lose weight you will have
better skin you will have greater
immunity you will be happier in your
mind as well as in your body thank you
so much pooja
one last question that will take I see
so many of them questioning but they
pick the best question which I think is
well suited for people to know and that
question is can be all eat chicken
during this time of couvade 19 or egg
yes or no in the current scenario
question by Sami Becky so at the moment
we have been given no reason to avoid
the the virus is not affecting the
animals and if you are cooking your food
whether it is vegetarian or
non-vegetarian the virus is very heat
sensitive so it deactivates its RNA and
kills it so any food that is cooked
whether it is vegetarian or
non-vegetarian is safe for consumption
so I would not say that you have to
avoid eating any type of food the only
food that you should be careful and
cautious about is raw food
I'm so glad pooja you made that point
about that you can eat chicken and egg
because while you cook it while you eat
it or while you boil it it kills all
that is there and it's quite suitable
for your L to eat it thank you so much
pooja Mejia for joining us here at the
Wellness 360 at home and brought to you
by Isis in the bar this one quick
question that I wanna ask you I drink
honey water with lemon every morning
I start my day with beetroot every
single day with an orange I make sure I
meditate for half an hour a day I
workout for one hour
is that a good way to start a day it's a
great way to start the day the only
thing I would change Mithun is the warm
water with lemon I do not think I don't
think that's the best thing to do to
your body so according to a lot of
Sciences warm water with lemon is the
nature of calcium from your bones so it
is not something I recommend to anybody
to do so honey I do not like all of us
are sweet enough and all of us are
getting enough sugar from the food we
eat so I do not
in any added sugar that also on a daily
basis but warm water with lemon is the
best way to get bone related aches and
pains so if I were you I would stop that
immediately so that would be my first
personal advice to you and to everyone
else who's listening in in this
360-degree life of wellness from home
I'm sorry is to do not do warm water
with lemon
it causes leaching of calcium from your
bones and therefore bone related aches
and pains over a period of time so stop
that other than that I think you're
doing well missing so keep it up thank
you so much who the trustee uses answer
something very amazing because I've been
doing the last three years and I'm like
there's something really wrong with it
so glad I questioned you thank you so
much for joining us at wellness 360 at
home it was great and our viewers loved
it and all I can say is thank you so
much and Namaskar from the whole of
ICICI Lombard for joining us here thank
you thank you everyone take care be safe
be home and be very very positive that's
important that's right
be positive thank you so much that was
pooja Mejia giving us a complete insight
about how one should take care of the
body the family members and much more
whether you're vegetarian or
non-vegetarian make sure you plan what
you eat throughout today and once you
start planning that and you know about
you intakes you can always control
majority of the problems that happens as
you become older so yes
that was a very interesting session on
wellness you know what to eat now what
intake should be there you protein the
zinc and much more so make sure your
immune as communicant be be the best
version of who you are because all we
are trying to do here and the Wellness
260th book is make you the best you are
thank you again in case you have any
feedback or suggestion please go on to a
Facebook page your hashtag wellness 360
at-home tag I see a yellow bird and
we'll be more than happy to answer to
all your questions and suggestions
my name is Bethune apotheon you can also
follow me on Instagram
and thank you so much for joining us
we'll see you in the next episode
meanwhile be happy be healthy keep
smiling keep laughing and we will see
you very soon thank you for joining us
you